<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Culture on The CTO Trap</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Culture on The CTO Trap</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>To Evolve and Mingle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-02-19-how_i_wanna_work_pt3-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-02-19-how_i_wanna_work_pt3-team/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A successful team is essential for the company and the group itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This question pops up sooner or later in any job interview: How do you imagine your perfect workplace?&#xA;Anybody has an idea of what and how they want to work if they could choose freely.&#xA;The most critical part is The T.E.A.M. (or To Evolve And Mingle)!&#xA;The people I&amp;rsquo;m spending more time with on weekdays than with my wife or my kid. The folks I&amp;rsquo;m trusting are doing their jobs the best way they can - just as they trust me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The power of the mind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-09-13-how_i_wanna_work_pt2-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-09-13-how_i_wanna_work_pt2-mindset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The mindset influences the success of a company - and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A company&amp;rsquo;s mindset is defined by how people work together, communicate, and view their work/product. An attractive attitude for me would be that people follow the Agile Manifesto daily, have an honest, open, and same-level type of communication, and are proud of their product, work, and company.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot; Please describe your ideal workplace&amp;quot; is a typical question in a job interview.&#xA;Even though it seems like a standard question to check if the candidate would be a match, the actual intent of this question is to see if the candidate has a clear opinion on his working environment and can articulate that.&#xA;So, whenever I&amp;rsquo;m hiring for a dev/DevOps/it position, this question will eventually pop up at one point or another during the process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a vision</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-08-15-how_i_wanna_work_pt1-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-08-15-how_i_wanna_work_pt1-vision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why having a vision is the most important thing for a successful venture.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;creating-a-vision&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Creating a vision&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#creating-a-vision&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog, The CTO trap, where I share my thoughts and insights on how I want to work in the modern world.&#xA;I started this blog because I am passionate about creating positive change through technology and innovation. I believe that work is more than just a way to earn money. It is a way to express ourselves, to create value, and to make a positive impact on the world. I also believe that work can be fun, fulfilling, and meaningful if we have a clear vision of what we want to achieve and how we want to achieve it.&#xA;In this first post, I want to discuss the importance of having a vision for our work and career. A vision is a mental picture of the future we desire. It is not a goal, a plan, or a strategy. It is a dream, a purpose, or a cause. A vision is what motivates us, inspires us, and guides us. A vision is what makes us different from others and what makes us stand out.&#xA;Why is having a vision vital?&#xA;Having a vision is essential for several reasons. First, a vision gives us direction. It helps us to focus on what matters most and to avoid distractions and temptations. It helps us to prioritize our actions and to align them with our values and principles. It helps us make decisions and solve problems. It helps us to measure our progress and to celebrate our achievements.&#xA;Second, a vision gives us meaning. It helps us to understand why we do what we do and how we contribute to something bigger than ourselves. It helps us to connect with our passion and our potential. It helps us to find joy and satisfaction in our work and to overcome challenges and setbacks. It helps us to grow and to learn.&#xA;Third, a vision gives us influence. It helps us to communicate our ideas and our values to others. It helps us attract and inspire people who share our vision and want to join us. It helps us to create a culture and a community around our vision and to make a positive difference in the world.&#xA;What are the results of lacking a vision?&#xA;Lacking a vision can have negative consequences for our work and our careers. Without a vision, we may feel lost, confused, or bored. We may lack motivation, enthusiasm, or creativity. We may settle for less than we deserve or chase after things that don’t matter. We may waste our time, energy, and resources on activities that don’t align with our values and principles. We may miss opportunities or make mistakes that could have been avoided.&#xA;We may feel isolated, frustrated, or unhappy without a vision. We may struggle to find meaning and purpose in our work and to connect with others who share our interests and goals. We may feel dissatisfied with our work and results and doubt ourselves and our abilities. We may lose confidence and credibility and fail to reach our full potential.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
